<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Homer Durand</title>
    <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Homer Durand</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 23:29:21 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Out-of-distribution Generalisation via Diluted Causality</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/anchor_mva/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/anchor_mva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📄 &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.01865&#34;&gt;Paper accepted at AISTATS 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;em&gt;diluted causality&lt;/em&gt; comes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1812.08233&#34;&gt;Bühlmann (2018)&lt;/a&gt;, inspired by a suggestion from &lt;a href=&#34;https://statistics.wharton.upenn.edu/profile/edgeorge/&#34;&gt;Edward George&lt;/a&gt;. It reflects the notion that while causal mechanisms are expected to be invariant under all possible interventions, a weaker form of invariance—&lt;em&gt;diluted causality&lt;/em&gt;—can be more desirable in practice. This weaker notion restricts the set of interventions to those most relevant for predictive generalisation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project investigates the interplay between &lt;strong&gt;causality&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;invariance&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;out-of-distribution (OOD) generalisation&lt;/strong&gt;. It builds upon influential work by Peter Bühlmann, Nicolai Meinshausen, Jonas Peters, Dominik Rothenhäusler, Rune Christiansen, and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History Matching for climate model tuning - experiments on the Lorenz96 toy model</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/history_matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/history_matching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;base target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my end-of-study internship at the LOCEAN-IPSL laboratory, I have been working on coupled ocean-atmosphere models calibration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ccentral goal of the the project was to better understand if History Matching technique was adapated for calibrating coupled ocean-atmosphere models. Using a simplified model, the two layers Lorenz-96 we demonstrated that History Matching method effectively constrained the model&amp;rsquo;s parameter search space. Notably, this was validated across scenarios resembling AMIP (Atmospheric Model Intercomparison Project) and OMIP (Ocean Model Intercomparison Project) experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for the detection of Deficient MMR Crypts to aid in the diagnosis of Lynch Disease</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/lynch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/lynch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;base target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lynch Syndrome is associated with a significantly elevated risk of developing colorectal cancer (CRC). However, this risk can be mitigated through early detection and intervention. A pivotal diagnostic method involves identifying lesions in enterocytes using immunohistochemistry on colon tissue samples. A deficient Mismatch Repair (MMR) crypt, termed Adenomatous Crypt Foci (ACF), indicates Lynch Syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Distinguishing healthy and deficient crypts involves assessing their visual characteristics under a microscope, with healthy crypts appearing brown and ACF crypts blue. Other distinguishing criteria are explored in this project. Yet, the rarity of ACF crypts coupled with the manual microscopic examination by specialists - around 15 minutes per slide - hinders efficient diagnosis, with a single patient&amp;rsquo;s results taking around 2.5 hours due to multiple slides.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
