<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Example on Homer Durand</title>
    <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/tags/example/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Example on Homer Durand</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 23:29:21 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/tags/example/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>High-Dimensional Regression - Study of the Debiased Lasso Estimator</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/debiased_lasso/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/debiased_lasso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Description of the project&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for the detection of Deficient MMR Crypts to aid in the diagnosis of Lynch Disease</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/lynch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/lynch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;base target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lynch Syndrome is associated with a significantly elevated risk of developing colorectal cancer (CRC). However, this risk can be mitigated through early detection and intervention. A pivotal diagnostic method involves identifying lesions in enterocytes using immunohistochemistry on colon tissue samples. A deficient Mismatch Repair (MMR) crypt, termed Adenomatous Crypt Foci (ACF), indicates Lynch Syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Distinguishing healthy and deficient crypts involves assessing their visual characteristics under a microscope, with healthy crypts appearing brown and ACF crypts blue. Other distinguishing criteria are explored in this project. Yet, the rarity of ACF crypts coupled with the manual microscopic examination by specialists - around 15 minutes per slide - hinders efficient diagnosis, with a single patient&amp;rsquo;s results taking around 2.5 hours due to multiple slides.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric Density and Survival Function Estimation - Multiplicative Censoring Model</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/nonparametric_density_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/nonparametric_density_estimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Description of the project&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Machine Learning - Study of the Median of Mean estimator</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/mom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/mom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Description of the project&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History Matching for climate model tuning - experiments on the Lorenz96 toy model</title>
      <link>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/history_matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 23:29:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugo-profile.netlify.app/projects/history_matching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;base target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my recent end-of-study internship at the LOCEAN-IPSL laboratory, I delved into the intriguing realm of coupled ocean-atmosphere models calibration. This report unveils the outcomes of this exploration, along with the novel research directions that emerged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The central inquiry of this project revolves around the applicability of the History Matching technique, also known as Iterative Refocussing, in fine-tuning coupled ocean-atmosphere models. Using a simplified model, the Lorenz-96, which can be seen as an approximation of an Atmosphere Ocean General Circulation Model, I demonstrated the potency of the History Matching method in effectively constraining the model&amp;rsquo;s parameter search space. Notably, this breakthrough was validated across scenarios resembling AMIP (Atmospheric Model Intercomparison Project) and OMIP (Ocean Model Intercomparison Project) experiments. In AMIP-style setups, a pared-down atmosphere model reacts to ocean observations, while in OMIP-style experiments, a simplified ocean model responds to atmospheric observations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
