<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic Interests on Homer Durand</title>
    <link>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic Interests on Homer Durand</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;em&gt;The Book of Why: The New Science of Cause and Effect&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://bayes.cs.ucla.edu/WHY/&#34;&gt;J.Pearl, 2018&lt;/a&gt;) recently introduced me to an absolutely fascinating field of research. At the junction of statistics and theoretical computer science, it interests me both in the questions it raises in our relationship to science and in the various applications it allows. So I am currently supplementing my knowledge on this subject by reading the books &lt;em&gt;Causality&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://bayes.cs.ucla.edu/BOOK-2K/&#34;&gt;J.Pearl, 2009&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;Element of Causal Inference&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://library.oapen.org/bitstream/id/056a11be-ce3a-44b9-8987-a6c68fce8d9b/11283.pdf&#34;&gt;Pearl &amp;amp; al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;). As part of my PhD, I am actually particularly developping &lt;em&gt;Causal Representation Learning&lt;/em&gt; methods for spatio-temporal data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth System Sciences</title>
      <link>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to climate science and the study of the Earth system as a whole in a course given by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipsl.fr/l-ipsl/connaitre-lipsl/herve-le-treut/&#34;&gt;Hervé Le Treut&lt;/a&gt; during my preparatory classes. Since then, I have been interested in scientific issues related to earth system modelling, which is why I did my final year internship at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.locean-ipsl.upmc.fr/index.php?lang=fr&#34;&gt;Locéan&lt;/a&gt; laboratory on the issues of tuning coupled ocean-atmosphere models using machine learning and Bayesian optimisation methods (&lt;em&gt;History Matching&lt;/em&gt;). You may read my &lt;a href=&#34;https://homerdurand.github.io/home/recentworks/reports/LOCEAN_report.pdf&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; for more information about the work I did there.I am currently pursuing this path by doing my PhD at the IPL where I am developing Causal Representation Learning methods for the Earth Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Methods</title>
      <link>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the course of my career I have developed a great interest in Kernel methods, whether for their mathematical elegance, the diversity of methods they allow to develop or the variety of applications in which they are a precious tool. I am now working on the development of Causal Representation Learning methods relying mainly on notions of independence in &lt;em&gt;Reproducing Kernel Hilbert Spaces&lt;/em&gt; (as it as been proposed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jmlr.org/papers/volume5/fukumizu04a/fukumizu04a.pdf&#34;&gt;Fukumizu &amp;amp; al., 2004&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10618-022-00832-5&#34;&gt;Cheng &amp;amp; al., 2022&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric inference</title>
      <link>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://homerdurand.github.io/home/services/service4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having discovered non-parametric inference during a &lt;a href=&#34;https://homerdurand.github.io/home/recentworks/rw_6/&#34;&gt;statistical learning project&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to develop my knowledge of this field of research in statistics and data science during an introductory course on non-parametric methods supervised by &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/charlottedionblanc/&#34;&gt;Charlotte Dion-Blanc&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lpsm.paris/pageperso/castillo/&#34;&gt;Ismael Castillo&lt;/a&gt;), for which I carried out a &lt;a href=&#34;https://homerdurand.github.io/home/recentworks/rw_2/&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; on the estimation of density and survival function by kernel methods within the framework of the multiplicative censoring model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
